Guide to the Aldous Huxley Collection, 1922-1934
Department of Special Collections
Aldous Huxley Collection,
1922-1934
Special Collections M0107
Huxley, Aldous, 1894-1963.
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Scope and Content
The collection contains letters and telegrams from Aldous Huxley's literary agents--James B. Pinker and Sons--to various persons, periodicals, etc. pertaining to Mr. Huxley's writings. These date from 1922 to 1934. This collection is not complete; for instance there are letters for May, 1931, the only correspondence for 1931. The literary agents had offices in New York City where Eric Pinker was in charge, and in London, where Ralph Pinker was in charge. The correspondence is mainly from them to various persons, or agencies, as for example Chatto and Windus in London.
The collection also contains
excerpts from Christopher Wren
typescript of Man's Most Dangerous Myth
typescript of Success (scenario)
typescript of Beyond the Swarm
address: Words and their Meaning
original corrected typescript of Antic Hay
Two autographed letters from Huxley and postcard to Van Patten.
Letters # 422-424 only ones by Huxley
1912 Sketchbook with original Huxley drawings in pencil and color, separated and cataloged as Misc 168.
Biographical Note
English author.
Container List
- TELEGRAMS: STATEMENTS FROM PUBLISHERS (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1--Telegrams: 13 (1927-1933)
  - 2--Statements to Pinker & Sons
    - a) Marshall Typing Service--, 1
    - b) Chatto & Windus--, 1
    - c) British Broadcasting Co.--, 1
    - d) Daily Herald--, 2
    - r) Collins & Son--, 1
    - f) Sunday Referee Publishing Co.--, 4
    - g) New York American--, 43
    - h) Hutchins & Co.--, [UNK]
- CORRESPONDENCE FROM PUBLISHERS, 1922-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  (Unless otherwise noted, the following are addressed to Pinker)
  - 1) E. Kilday, March, 1922
  - 2) CB, June, 1922
  - 3) Time and Tide to J.B. Pinker, Nov., 1922
  - 4)Chatto & Windus (London), Jan., 1923
  - 5) The Outlook (london), Jan., 1923
  - 6) George H. Doran Co., Feb., 1923
  - 7) The Criterion (London), Feb., 1923
  - 8) George H. Doran (N.Y.C.), May, 1923
  - 9) ENB, May, 1923
  - 10) Percy Spalding (London), May, 1923
  - 11) George H. Doran, May, 1923
  - 12) E.N. Brandt, July, 1923
  - 13) CB, July, 1923
  - 14) Geo. H. Doran (N.Y.C.), Aug., 1923
  - 15) Geo. H. Doran, Aug., 1923
  - 16) Chatto & Windus (London), Aug., 1923
  - 17) Chatto & Windus (London), Sept., 1923
  - 18) Chatto & Windus, Oct., 1923
  - 19) Geo. H. Doran (N.Y.C.), Oct., 1923
  - 20) Chatto & Windus (London), Oct., 1923
  - 21) J.A.M. Hunter (Isle of Wight), Oct., 1923
  - 22) Geo. H. Doran (N.Y.C.), Nov., 1923
  - 23) Geo. H. Doran (N.Y.C.), Nov., 1923
  - 24) CB, Nov., 1923
  - 25) Cassell & Co., Ltd. Olondon), Nov., 1923
  - 26) Chatto & Windus, Jan., 1924
  - 27) Cornhill Magazine (London), Jan., 1924
  - 28) Geo. H. Doran, Jan., 1924
  - 29) Cornhill Mag., Jan., 1924
  - 30) Geo. H. Doran, April, 1924
  - 31) Dinndale Stocker (London), May, 1924
  - 32) The Sketch Mag. (London), May, 1924
  - 33) Chatto & Windus (London), May, 1933
  - 34) Victor Dana (Paris), May, 1924
  - 35) Chatto & Windus, May, 1924
  - 36) Der Nike Verlag to Chatto & Windus (Berlin), May, 1924
  - 37) Chatto & Windus, May, 1924
  - 38) Der Nike Verlag (Berlin), May, 1924
  - 39) A. Hamilton Gibbs, May, 1924
  - 40) Der Nike Verlag, May, 1924
  - 41) David Grunbaum (Copenhagen), June, 1924
  - 42) Geo. H. Doran, June, 1924
  - 43) A. Hamilton Gibbs, June, 1924
  - 44) Geo. H. Doran, June, 1924
  - 45) Cornhill Mag., June, 1924
  - 46) Geo, H. Doran, Oct., 1924
  - 47) Chatto & Windus, Oct., 1924
  - 48) G. Wm. Breck, Oct., 1924
  - 49) Geo. H. Doran, Oct., 1924
  - 50) Anne-Marie von Held (Coblenz), Oct., 1924
  - 51) Anne-Marie von Held (Coblenz), Nov., 1924
  - 52) Chatto & Windus, Nov., 1924
  - 53) Chatto & Windus, Nov., 1924
  - 54) Geo. H. Doran, Nov., 1924
  - 55) Geo. H. Doran, Feb., 1925
  - 56) Nannine V. Joseph, Feb., 1925
  - 57) Geo. H. Doran, Feb., 1925
  - 58) The Sphere (LOndon), Feb., 1925
  - 59) Conservative Review (London), Feb., 1925
  - 60) Nation and Athenaeum (London), Feb., 1925
  - 61) Mary Killerman and Marshall Bullitt, to Huxley, Berlin, Feb., 1925
  - 62) David Grunbaum (Copenhagen), Feb., 1925
  - 63) Conservative Review, Feb., 1925
  - 64) Curtis Brown, Ltd. (London), Feb., 1925
  - 65) Wm. Collins Sons, Feb., 1925
  - 66) Chatto & Windus, Feb., 1925
  - 67) E.N. Brandt, March, 1925
  - 68) Brandt & Brandt, March, 1925
  - 69) Geo. H. Doran, March, 1925
  - 70) Nation and Athenaeum, March, 1925
  - 71) Clarisse Meitner (Vienna), March, 1925
  - 72) From Dr. Ewald to Chatto & Windus (Berlin), March, 1925
  - 73) Chatto & Windus, March, 1925
  - 74) Dr. Weald to Pinker (Berlin), April, 1925
  - 75) Chatto & Windus, April, 1925
  - 76) Hutchinson & Co., April, 1925
  - 77) Geo. H. Doran, April, 1925
  - 78) Geo. H. Doran, April, 1925
  - 79) Geo. H. Doran, April, 1925
  - 80) E. Herlitschka (Vienna), April, 1925
  - 81) David Grunbaum (Copenhagen), April, 1925
  - 82) Chatto & Windus, April, 1925
  - 83) The Times (London), Dec., 1925
  - 84) C. C. Brookfield (London), Dec., 1925
  - 85) C. C. Brookfield, Dec., 1925
  - 86) Yoi Maraini (Firenze), Dec., 1925
  - 87) Geo. H. Doran, Dec., 1925
- CORRESPONDENCE FROM PUBLISHERS, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 88) The Observer (London), Feb., 1926
  - 89) Chatto & Windus (London), Feb., 1926
  - 90) Geo. H. Doran, Feb., 1926
  - 91) Elizabeth Haufstanan to Blackwood & Sons, Feb., 1926
  - 92) Revista de Occidente to Chatto & Windus (Madrid), May, 1926
  - 93) The Nation, May, 1926
  - 94) Chatto & Windus, May, 1926
  - 95) Geo. H. Doran, May, 1926
  - 96) Chatto & Windus, May, 1926
  - 97) Dulan & Co., Ltd. (London), May, 1926
  - 98) Chatto & Windus, July, 1926
  - 99) Bernard Tauchnitz (Leipsig), July, 1926
  - 100) Geo. H. Doran, July, 1926
  - 101) Nannine Joseph (Brandt & Brandt), July, 1926
  - 102) Geo. H. Doran, July, 1926
  - 103) Geo. H. Doran, July, 1926
  - 104) Chatto & Windus, July, 1926
  - 105) Franz Fein (Berlin), July, 1926
  - 106) Time and Tide, July, 1926
  - 107) Daily Express (London), Aug, 1926
  - 108) M. Moynilian (London), Aug, 1926
  - 109) The Outlook, Aug, 1926
  - 110) The Outlook, Sept., 1926
  - 111) Nannine Joseph, Sept., 1926
  - 112) Little, Brown Co., Sept., 1926
  - 113) Oxford Univ. Press (London), Sept., 1926
  - 114) Nannine Joseph, Sept., 1926
  - 115) La Renaissance du Louvre (Paris), Sept., 1926
  - 116) Chatto & Windus, Sept., 1926
  - 117) Bernard Tauchnitz (Leipsig), Nov., 1926
  - 118) Chatto & Windus, Nov., 1926
  - 119) Chatto & Windus, Nov., 1926
  - 120) H. C. Tracy (Berkeley, Calif.), Dec., 1926
  - 121) Brandt and Brandt to Huxley, Dec., 1926
  - 122) Nannine Joseph, Dec., 1926
  - 123) Georgette Camille (Paris), Dec., 1926
  - 124) Chatto & Windus, Jan, 1927
  - 125) Clarisse Meitner, July, 1927
  - 126) Chatto & Windus, July, 1927
  - 127) Anglo-American Academic Bureau to Chatto & Windus, July, 1927
  - 128) Chatto & Windus, July, 1927
  - 129) Jonathan Cape Ltd., Aug., 1927
  - 130) Geo. H. Doran, Aug., 1927
  - 131) Geo. H. Doran, Aug., 1927
  - 132) Chatto & Windus, Sept., 1927
  - 133) Chatto & Windus, Sept., 1927
  - 134) Ernest Hitschman, Nov., 1927
  - 135) George G. Harrap & Co. to F. C. Wicken, Nov., 1927
  - 136) Wicken to Harrap, Nov., 1927
  - 137) National Library for Blind to Chatto & Windus, Nov., 1927
  - 138) Herberth E. [UNK], Nov., 1927
  - 139) Bernard Tauchnitz to Wicken, Nov., 1927
- CORRESPONDENCE FROM PUBLISHERS, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 140) Hutchinson's Per. Co. (London), Jan., 1928
  - 141) Bertha Evans Ward (Cincinnati), Jan., 1928
  - 142) Chatto & Windus, Feb., 1928
  - 143) Herberth E. Herlitschka, Feb., 1928
  - 144) Chatto & Windus, Feb., 1928
  - 145) Jean Ably (Paris), Feb., 1928
  - 146) Chatto & Windus, Feb., 1928
  - 147) Dr. Maria Strasny (Wien), March, 1928
  - 148) Chatto & Windus, March, 1928
  - 149) Dr. Maria Strasny (Wien), March, 1928
  - 150) Peter von Hamm to Huxley (Berlin), May, 1928
  - 151) Chatto & Windus, May, 1928
  - 152) Peter von Hamm, May, 1928
  - 153) National Library for Blind to Chatto & Windus (Westminster), May, 1928
  - 154) M. E. Eubach (Vienna), May, 1928
  - 155) Leeds Art Theatre (leeds), May, 1928
  - 156) Herberth E. Herlitschka, May, 1928
  - 157) Kra, Editeur (Paris), June, 1928
  - 158) Doubleday, Doran (London), June, 1928
  - 159) Chatto & Windus, June, 1928
  - 160) Crosby Gaige (N.Y.C.), June, 1928
  - 161) Pinker to Pinker, June, 1928
  - 162) Insel-Verlag (Leiosig), July, 1928
  - 163) Kra, Editeur (Paris), July, 1928
  - 164) Chatto & Windus, July, 1928
  - 165) Chatto & Windus, July, 1928
  - 166) Miriam [UNK] to Ralph Pinker (N.Y.C.), July, 1928
  - 167) Chatto & Windus, Aug., 1928
  - 168) Chatto & Windus, Aug., 1928
  - 169) National Library for Blind, Aug., 1928
  - 170) The Nation, Sept., 1928
  - 171) The Spectator, Sept., 1928
  - 172) International Mag. Co., Sept., 1928
  - 173) Chatto & Windus, Sept., 1928
  - 174) Pinker to Pinker, Sept., 1928
  - 175) Chatto & Windus, Oct., 1928
  - 176) Chatto & Windus, Oct., 1928
  - 177) Dr. Marie L. Barker to Chatto & Windus (Edinburgh), Oct., 1928
  - 178) Chatto & Windus, Oct., 1928
  - 179) Chatto & Windus, Oct., 1928
  - 180) Bernhard Tauchnitz, Oct., 1928
  - 181) Gertrude D. Bleistein to Chatto & Windus, Oct., 1928
  - 182) Miriam [UNK] to Ralph Pinker, Oct., 1928
  - 183) Chatto & Windus, Oct., 1928
  - 184) The Spectator, Oct., 1928
  - 185) Blau-[UNK] to Chatto & Windus, Oct., 1928
  - 186) Blau-Rot to Pinker, Oct., 1928
  - 187) Chatto & Windus-, Oct., 1928
  - 188) Bernard Tauchnits, Oct., 1928
  - 189) Agenzia Litteraria Internazionale (Torino), Dec., 1928
  - 190) Bernard Tauchnitz, Dec., 1928
  - 191) Francisca Weald (Berlin), Dec., 1928
  - 192) Aline Kirchner to Chatto & Windus, Dec., 1928
  - 193) The Spectator, Dec., 1928
  - 194) Two unsigned letters to Huxley, Jan., 1928; (copies)
- CORRESPONDENCE FROM PUBLISHERS, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 195) The Bystander (London), Jan, 1929
  - 196) Chatto & Windus, Jan, 1929
  - 197) Daily News, Jan, 1929
  - 198) Doubleday Doran, Jan, 1929
  - 199) International Mag. Co., Jan, 1929
  - 200) Doubleday, Doran & Co., Jan, 1929
  - 201) Miss Alice Weisskopf, Jan, 1929
  - 202) Chatto & Windus, Jan, 1929
  - 203) British National Newspaper, Jan, 1929
  - 204) H. Barnes (Master at Central School compiling essays for school use for Harrap & Co.) Leeds, Jan, 1929
  - 205) Kitty Kind to Pinker (Austria), Jan, 1929
  - 206) J. Paul (?) (London), April, 1929
  - 207) Eric Pinker to Miss, Amy Dyson (NYC), April, 1929
  - 208) Chatto & Windus, April, 1929
  - 209) Herberth E. Herlitschka (Vienna), April, 1929
  - 210) Harpers Magazine, April, 1929
  - 211) Pinker (?) to Huxley, April, 1929
  - 212) Eric Pinker to Miss Amy Dyson, April, 1929
  - 213) Eric Pinker to Miss Amy Dyson, April, 1929
  - 214) Chatto & Windus, May, 1929
  - 215) Herberth E. Herlitschka (Leipsig), May, 1929
  - 216) A. Baur-Corradi (?) to Chatto & Windus, May, 1929
  - 217) Herberth E. Herlitschka, May, 1929
  - 218) Editions Kra (Paris), May, 1929
  - 219) Mandrake Press (London), May, 1929
  - 220) Mandrake Press (London), May, 1929
  - 221) Chatto & Windus, May, 1929
  - 222) European Books, Ltd. to Pinker, May, 1929
  - 223) Librairie Plon to Pinker (?), July 1929
  - 224) Editions Kra, July, 1929
  - 225) D. R. Gelly (?) to Pinker (?) (London), July, 1929
  - 226) Pinker & Sons to Miss V. Barton (NYC), July, 1929
  - 227) Chatto & Windus, July, 1929
  - 228) Chatto & Windus, August, 1929
  - 229) Librairie Plon to Pinker (Paris), August, 1929
  - 230) Fountain Press to Pinker (NYC), August, 1929
  - 231) David Grunbaum (Copenhagen), August, 1929
  - 232) Atlantic Monthly, October, 1929
  - 233) Agenzia Letterarie International (Torino), October, 1929
  - 234) Martha Junkerman to Constable Co. (Vienna), October, 1929
  - 235) Pinker to Pinker, October, 1929
  - 236) Oxford Univ. Press, October, 1929
  - 237) Oxford Univ. Press, October, 1929
  - 238) Yale Review, Nov., 1929
  - 239) Wasnicka & Hampl to Doubleday, Doran, Nov., 1929
  - 240) Doubleday, Doran to K & H, Nov., 1929
  - 241) Doubleday, Doran, Nov., 1929
  - 242) Mrs. Huxley, No Date
  - 243) Victoria Art Gallery & Municipal Libraries (Bath), Feb., 1930
  - 244) Herberth E. Herlitschka, Sept., 1930
  - 245) Jespersen Og Pios [UNK] (Copenhagen), Sept., 1930
  - 246) Pinker to Pinker, Sept., 1930
  - 247) Harpers, Sept., 1930
  - 248) Pinker to Pinker, Sept., 1930
  - 249) Herberth E. Herlitschke, Sept., 1930
  - 250) Thomas Nelson, Sept., 1930
  - 251) Chatto & Windus, Sept., 1930
  - 252) [UNK] Wydawnieze (Warsaw), Nov., 1930
  - 253) Doubleday, Doran, Nov., 1930
  - 254) Librairie Plon, Nov., 1930
  - 255) Librairie Stork, Nov., 1930
  - 256) Hibbert Journal to Pinker (?), Nov., 1930
  - 257) Pinker to Pinker, Nov., 1930
  - 258) Stasajellovska, Nov., 1930
  - 259) A. G. Paladini to Chatto & Windus, Nov., 1930
- CORRESPONDENCE FROM PUBLISHERS, 1931-1932; n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 260) Nash's Pall Mall Magazine to Pinker, May, 1931
  - 261) Doubleday, Doran (NYC), May, 1931
  - 262) Albin Michel to Chatto & Windus (Paris), May, 1931
  - 263) Republic, May, 1931
  - 264) W. Colston Leigh, Inc. (NYC), May, 1931
  - 265) Doubleday, Doran, May, 1931
  - 266) David Grunbaum (Copenhagen), May, 1931
  - 267) David Grunbaum (Copenhagen), May, 1931
  - 268) The Albatross (Paris), Aug., 1932
  - 269) Herberth E. Herlitschka (Copenhagen), Aug., 1932
  - 270) Mme. Jeanne Leonard, Aug., 1932
  - 271) Harper & Brothers (London?), Aug., 1932
  - 272) Mme. J. Leonard (Vence), Aug., 1932
  - 273) Nash's Pall Mall (London), Aug., 1932
  - 274) William Morrow (NYC), Aug., 1932
  - 275) Geo. H. Doran (London), Aug., 1932
  - 276) Nash's Pall Mall, Aug., 1932
  - 277) Agenzia Letteria Internazionale (Milan), Aug., 1932
  - 278) Editions du Siecle to Chatto & Windus (Paris), Aug., 1932
  - 279) Univ. of Toronto to Huxley, Aug., 1932
  - 280) Editions du Siecle, Aug., 1932
  - 281) Nash Pall Mall, Aug., 1932
  - 282) Agenzia Litteraria Internazionale (Milan), Sept., 1932
  - 283) Agenzia Internazionale (Milan), Sept., 1932
  - 284) Editions du Siecle to Pinker, Sept., 1932
  - 285) National Mag. Co., Sept., 1932
  - 286) Wm. Leon Smyser (Austria), Sept., 1932
  - 287) Librairie Plon, Sept., 1932
  - 288) Editions du Siecle, Sept., 1932
  - 289) Harcourt, Brace & Co., Sept., 1932
  - 290) Geo. H. Doran (London), Sept., 1932
  - 291) Geo. H. Doran (London), Sept., 1932
  - 292) Harpers & Brothers (London), Sept., 1932
  - 293) Towarzystwo [UNK] (Warsaw), Sept., 1932
  - 294) Wm. Leon Smyser (Vienna), Sept., 1932
  - 295) Harper & Bros., Sept., 1932
  - 296) Librairie Plon, Sept., 1932
  - 297) Editions du Siecle, Sept., 1932
  - 298) Herberth E. Herlitschka, Dec., 1932
  - 299) Herberth E. Herlitschka, Dec., 1932
  - 300) Nash's Pall Mall Mag., Dec., 1932
  - 301) Henri Delmas to Chatto & Windus, Dec., 1932
  - 302) Miss S. Pauf to Pinker (?) Paris, Dec., 1932
  - 303) Librairie Plon, Dec., 1932
  - 304) Kazimierz Bukowski to Pinker (?), No Date
- CORRESPONDENCE FROM PUBLISHERS, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 305) Memorandum --Geo. Doran, Jan., 1933
  - 306) David Grunbaum, Jan., 1933
  - 307) Nash's Pall Mall Mag., Jan., 1933
  - 308) Agence International Litteraire to Chatte & Windus (Paris), Jan., 1933
  - 309) Librairie Plon, Jan., 1933
  - 310) Nina Polousky Saunders to Chatto & Windus, Jan., 1933
  - 311) Dial Press (NYC), Jan., 1933
  - 312) Librairie Plon, Jan., 1933
  - 313) Towarzystwo Wydawnicze, Jan., 1933
  - 314) Agenzia Letteraria Internazionale (Milan), May, 1933
  - 315) Chatto & Windus, May, 1933
  - 316) Herberth E. Herlitschka, May, 1933
  - 317) Agence Internationale Litteraire, May, 1933
  - 318) B.B. Ray Chaudhuri to Huxley, May, 1933
  - 319) Cliche Dept. to Pinker (London), May, 1933
  - 320) Pantheon to Curtis Brown Ltd. (Budapest), May, 1933
  - 321) Curtis Brown (Paris), May, 1933
  - 322) Nash's Pall Mall, May, 1933
  - 323) Dr. Eva Schumann to Pinker (?), May, 1933
  - 324) Nash's Pall Mall, July, 1933
  - 325) Watanabe Fumire (Tokyo), July, 1933
  - 326) Ottavio Alberto Mannini to Chatto & Windus (Naples), July, 1933
  - 327) K.N. Misra to Pinker (?), July, 1933
  - 328) Chatto & Windus, July, 1933
  - 329) Heinrich Hauser to Pinker (?), Sept., 1933
  - 330) David Grunbaum, Sept., 1933
  - 331) Prof. Joseph Wunder (Budapest), Sept., 1933
  - 332) Chatto & Windus, Sept., 1933
  - 333) Pinker to Pinker, Sept., 1933
  - 334) Harper & Bros., Dec., 1933
  - 335) Nash's Pall Mall Mag., Dec., 1933
  - 336) Harper & Bros., Dec., 1933
  - 337) Chatto & Windus, Dec., 1933
  - 338) Marie Canaugh to Huxley(?), Dec., 1933
  - 339) The Albatross, Dec., 1933
  - 340) H. Aschehoug & Co. (Oslo), Dec., 1933
  - 341) Mary Abrams to W. Davis concerning Alien Tax for Huxley, Dec., 1933
  - 342) H. Aschehoug & Co., Dec., 1933
  - 343) Methuen & Co. (London), Dec., 1933
  - 344) Pinker to Pinker, Dec., 1933
  - 345) Ernest Benn Ltd. (London), Dec., 1933
  - 346) Agenzia Letteraria Internazionale (Milan), Dec., 1933
  - 347) Gaumont-British Picture Corporation, Dec., 1933
- CORRESPONDENCE FROM PUBLISHERS, 1934-1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 348) Harper & Bros. (London), Jan., 1934
  - 349) Chatto & Windus, Jan., 1934
  - 350) Brit. Broadcasting Co., Jan., 1934
  - 351) Daria Kamende (?) (Paris), Jan., 1934
  - 352) Brit. Broadcasting Co. (London), Jan., 1934
  - 353) David Grunbaum (Copenhagen), Jan., 1934
  - 354) W. Collins Sons & Co. (London), Jan., 1934
  - 355) Nash's Pall Mall Magazine, Jan., 1934
  - 356) Chatto & Windus, Jan., 1934
  - 357) David Grunbaum, Jan., 1934
  - 358) David Grunbaum, Jan., 1934
  - 359) David Grunbaum, Jan., 1934
  - 360) Franklin-Tarsulat (Budapest), Jan., 1934
  - 361) Architectural Review (London), Jan., 1934
  - 362) Chatto & Windus, Jan., 1934
  - 363) Time & Tide (London), Jan., 1934
  - 364) Herberth E. Herlitschka (Austria), Feb., 1934
  - 365) David Grunbaum, April, 1934
  - 366) W. Collins & Sons, April, 1934
  - 367) Pinker to Pinker, April, 1934
  - 368) Doubleday Doran, April, 1934
  - 369) Harper & Brothers, April, 1934
  - 370) Pinker to Doubleday [UNK] (NYC), April, 1934
  - 371) Doubleday Doran to Pinker, April, 1934
  - 372) Chatto & Windus, April, 1934
  - 373) David Grunbaum, April, 1934
  - 374) Harper & Bros., April, 1934
  - 375) Pinker to Doubledny [UNK], April, 1934
  - 376) Robert, Hartman to Chatto & Windus, April, 1934
  - 377) Chatto & Windus, April, 1934
  - 378) Life & Letters (London), April, 1934
  - 379) Mme. G. d'Estensan to Chatto & Windus, April, 1934
  - 380) Ada Verusio (Naples), April, 1934
  - 381) David Grunbaum (Copenhagen), May, 1934
  - 382) David Grunbaum (Copenhagen), May, 1934
  - 383) Librairie Plon (Paris), May, 1934
  - 384) MacMillan & Co. (London), May, 1934
  - 385) Agenzia Letteraria Internazionale, May, 1934
  - 386) Chatto & Windus, May, 1934
  - 387) MacMillan Co. of Canada (Toronto), May, 1934
  - 388) David Grunbaum, May, 1934
  - 389) Rotor News for Hispano-America to Chatto & Windus (London), May, 1934
  - 390) Chatto & Windus, May, 1934
  - 391) Librairie Gallimard, May, 1934
  - 392) Harper Bros., May, 1934
  - 393) Librairie Gallimard (Paris), June, 1934
  - 394) Iowa State Library to Chatto & Windus, June, 1934
  - 395) MacMillan & Co. (London), June, 1934
  - 396) Chatto & Windus, June, 1934
  - 397) Paul Winkler (Paris), June, 1934
  - 398) Bureau Sulamericain etc. to Chatto & Windus (Sao Paulo), June, 1934
  - 399) Harper & Bros., June, 1934
  - 400) Wm. Heineman (London), June, 1934
  - 401) Montessori Society to Chatto & Windus, June, 1934
  - 402) Albatross (Paris), June, 1934
  - 403) David Grunbaum, June, 1934
  - 404) Bureau Sulamericain to Huxley, June, 1934
  - 405) Eileen Merrie & Ricardo Crespo to Chatto & Windus ([UNK]), June, 1934
  - 406) William Heineman (London), June, 1934
  - 407) Chatto & Windus, July, 1934
  - 408) Eileen Merrie & Ricardo Crispo, July, 1934
  - 409) Insel-Verlag (Leipsig), July, 1934
  - 410) Presse Bresilienne (Paris), July, 1934
  - 411) New Thought Alliance to Chatto & Windus, Aug., 1934
  - 412) Eileen Merrie & Ricardo Crispo, Aug., 1934
  - 413) Bureau Sulamericain, Aug., 1934
  - 414) Companhia Editora Nacional, Aug., 1934
  - 415) Presse Bresilienne, Aug., 1934
  - 416) Brit. Broadcasting Co., Aug., 1934
  - 417) Fileen Merrie & [UNK] Crispo, Aug., 1934
  - 418) Brit. Broadcasting Co., Aug., 1934
  - 419)?? to Pinker, Aug., 1934
  - 420) Herberth E. Herlitschka, Oct., 1934
  - 421) Chatto & Windus Frag., No Date
  - 422) Huxley to Van Patten, April, 1932
  - 423) Letter from Huxley to Jake [UNK], June 2, [UNK]
  - 424) Huxley to Van Patten, July 28, 1943
- 425) Excerpts from Christopher Wren (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 426) Typescript of Man's Most Dangerous Myth. Montague's pamphlet. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 427) Typescript of Success (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 428) Typescript of Beyond the Swarm (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 429) Address--Words and Their Meaning (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 430) Autographs [UNK] (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 431) Corredted typescript of Antic Hay (Box 1, Folder 15)
Notes
File 6 letter from William Morrow. Co Aug. 10 1932 is erroneously filed. Does not appear to have any connection with a Huxley work.
File 7 The first 2 letters written by A. Huxly to Jake Zeillin in 1942 and 1943 Seem to be out of place in a correspondence marked Correspondence from publishers 1934.
replaced in proper order